本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
先生  恐怕你不用再检查了
<i>I'm afraid your services won't be required here, sir.</i>
我们的警员已经仔细检查过证据
<i>My men have examined the evidence,</i>
很明显这是一起意外事故
<i>and this is obviously an accident.</i>
意外事故  警官
还是
谋杀呢
什么
<i>What?!</i>
不要走开  神探福尔摩鸭  广告之后更精彩
<i>Duck-tective will return after these messages.</i>
那简直是只神鸭
That duck is a genius.
呃  离地面那么近很容易发现蛛丝马迹啊
Eh. It's easier to find clues when you're that close to the ground.
你是想说你比福尔摩鸭更会推理么
Are you saying you could outwit duck-tective?
梅宝  我可是有非常敏锐的观察能力的哟
Mabel, I have very keen powers of observation.
比如  我只通过你的呼气
For example, just by smelling your breath
就能知道你吃了
I can tell that you have been eating...
一整管牙膏
An entire tube of toothpaste?
-谁让它那么闪的 -嘿  伙计们
- It was so sparkly. - Hey, dudes!
你们绝对猜不到我发现了什么
You'll never guess what I found!
-埋藏的宝藏  -埋藏的
- Buried treasure! - Buried...
嘿  你抢我的话
Hey, I was gonna say that!
我打扫的时候找到了这个隐蔽在
So I was cleaning up when I found this secret door
墙纸后面的门
hidden behind the wallpaper.
给我吓坏了
It's crazy-bonkers-creepy.
哇哦  这是个神秘蜡像馆
Whoa! It's a secret wax museum.
就跟真的一样
They're so life-like.
除了这个
Except for that one.
哈喽
Hello!
哈哈  是我啦  斯坦叔公
Ha ha! It's just me, your Grunkle Stan!
（注：根据后续剧情，确定斯坦是叔公）
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
翻译： 芭小豆
校订： WaitinZ
■
后期： WaitinZ  leland
怪诞小镇  第一季第三集
Gravity Falls  S01E03  Headhunters
欢迎来到重力泉蜡像馆
Behold the Gravity Falls Wax museum.
这曾经可是我们最有名的景点之一
It was one of our most popular attractions!
我都快把它给忘了
Before I forgot all about it.
我都能记起来  成吉思汗  夏洛克・福尔摩斯
I got 'em all... Genghis Khan, Sherlock Holmes,
可能是  我也不知道啦  哥布林人
some kind of, I don't know, Goblin Man.
唔  有人觉得这有点让人发毛吗
Ooh! Is anyone else getting the creeps here?
这边是我最最喜欢的
And now for my personal favorite...
阿伯拉罕・林肯蜡像  就在
wax Abraham Lincoln, right over...
噢  不是吧  怎么会
oh, no! Come on!
谁忘了拉窗帘
Who left the blinds open?!
约翰・威尔克斯・布斯蜡像  我在看你哦
Wax John Wilkes Booth, I'm lookin' in your direction.
（注：演员，曾刺杀林肯总统）
蜡像要怎么修复呢
How do you fix a wax figure?
振作一点  斯坦叔公
Cheer up, Grunkle Stan.
-笑容哪里去啦  -哼
- Where's that smile? - Meh.
不用担心  斯坦叔公  我可以用这些蜡给你重新做一个
Don't worry, Grunkle Stan, I'll make you a new wax figure from all this old wax.
你真觉得你会做这种蜡像吗
You really think you could make one of these puppies?
斯坦叔公  我可是工艺大师
Grunkle Stan, I'm an arts and crafts master.
不然你觉得我为什么随身带着涂胶枪呢
Why do you think I always have this glue gun stuck to my arm?
-呃啊  -孩子  我喜欢你的进取心
- Eeech! - I like your gumption, kid.
虽然不知道啥叫进取心  不过谢谢啦
I don't know what that word means, but thank you.
迪普
Dipper.
来看看我的蜡像设计
What do you think of my wax figure idea?
它是个半人精灵公主
She's part fairy princess,
半马精灵公主
and part horse fairy princess.
我觉得你还是做个现实中的人物比较好
Maybe you should carve something from real life.
那就来个有粗壮臂膀的华夫饼如何
Like a waffle with big arms!
啊这个  或者  别的什么东西
Yo-kay, or, ya know, something else,
比如你的家庭成员啊
like someone in your family.
孩子们  看见我的裤子了吗
Kids! Have you seen my pants?
哦  得来全不费工夫  天助我也
O muse, you work in mysterious ways.
你姐姐干嘛对着天花板讲话
Why is your sister talking to the ceiling?
我觉得它应该更闪亮一点
I think it needs more glitter.
同意
Agreed.
我找到我的裤子了  但是现在我找不到
I found my pants, but now I'm missing my...
觉得怎么样呀
What do you think?
我觉得蜡像馆可以重新开张啦
I think the wax museum's back in business!
神秘蜡像博物馆
盛大重新开业
世界第八大奇迹
举世闻名
真不敢相信这么多人来参观
I can't believe this many people showed up.
可不是吗
I know, right?
也许他们是你叔公给钱请来的托儿之类的吧
Your uncle probably bribed 'em or something.
他贿赂我了
He bribed me.
乡亲们  我这个市民偶像兼神秘先生想必你们都久仰啦
You all know me, folks, town doll and Mr. Mystery.
拜托啦  女士们  控制好你们的情绪
Please, ladies! Control yourselves!
众所周知  鄙人经常给各位乡亲带来一些
As you know, I always bring the people of this fair town
不常见的新鲜玩意
novelties and befuddlements,
给大家带来了很多惊喜和尖叫
the likes of which the world has never known.
先不说我啦
But enough about me.
请看
Behold...
又一个我
Me!
现在有请  梅宝郎基罗发言
And now a word from our own Mabelangelo.
梅宝就好啦
It's Mabel.
感谢大家的光临
Thank you for coming.
我用我灵巧的双手制作了这个蜡像
I made this sculpture with my own two hands!
它饱含了我的汗水  泪水  血水
It's covered in my blood, sweat, tears,
和其他的液体
and other fluids.
哈哈  是啦
Heh heh. Yeah.
现在我开始回答问题  你
I will now take questions. You there.
我是老人麦戈科特  本地疯子
Old man McGucket, local kook.
蜡像有生命吗  第二个问题
Are the wax figures alive? And, follow-up question,
蜡像们起义了我能幸存吗
can I survive the wax man uprising?
呃  是的  可以  下一个问题
Um... Yes! Next question.
决心男托比  来自《重力泉八卦报》
Toby determined, Gravity Falls Gossiper.
请问你真的认为这东西可以堪称世界奇迹吗
Do you <i>really </i>think this constitutes a wonder of the world?
托比  你用火鸡浇油管冒充话筒
Your microphone's a turkey baster, Toby.
-确实  -下一个问题
- It certainly is. - Next question.
珊多拉・西梅内斯  我是个真正的记者
Shandra Jimenez, a <i>real </i>reporter.
你们的宣传单上说这里有免费的匹萨
Your fliers promised free pizza with admission to this event.
请问确有其事吗
Is this true?
-我也听说了  -快点分披萨
- That's what <i>I </i>heard. - Come on!
快给我匹萨
I want my pizza.
那是个打印错误
That was a typo.
晚安  各位
Good night, everyone!
吃我一拳
In your face!
我们再也不会来了
We're not coming back <i>here.</i>
我觉得还挺顺利
I think that went well.
天哪  看看这么多钱
Hot pumpkin pie! Look at all this cash!
这全都要归功于一个人
And I owe it all to one person...
他
This guy.
噢  还有你这个小家伙儿
Ooh! Yeah, you too, ya little gremlin.
现在你们赶紧去洗漱吧
Now, you kids wash up.
明天我们还得继续敲诈那些乡巴佬呢
We got another long day of fleecing rubes tomorrow.
快快
Go! Go!
啊  孩子们
Ahh, kids.
神探福尔摩鸭
<i>Well, duck-dective,</i>
你真的解决了这个案子哟
<i>it seems you've really "quacked" the case.</i>
别给我摆臭架子
蠢鸭子
Stupid duck.
我要去个厕所
Well, I'm gonna use the John.
你有没有什么需要呢
You need anything?
我爱死你了  呆在这儿别动哦
I love this guy! Don't you go nowhere.
-迪普  你想不想来一场牙膏比赛呀  -好啊
- Dipper, you wanna do a toothbrush race? - Okay.
不  不  不
No... No... Nooooo!
蜡像斯坦被  被谋杀了
Wax Stan! He's been... Murdered!
我起身去个厕所
I got up to use the John, right?
等我回来的时候  嘣  他的头不见了
And when I come back, blammo! He's headless!
我精美绝伦的手工作品被糟蹋了
My expert handcrafting besmirched.
被糟蹋了
Besmirched!!!
谁会做这样的事呢
Who would <i>do </i>something like this?
你怎么看呢  布拉布斯警官
What's your opinion, Sheriff Blubs?
其实  我们很乐于帮助乡亲们的啦
Look, we'd love to help you folks,
但是  面对现实吧  这个案子无解
but let's face the facts... this case is unsolvable.
什么  你把这句话给我收回去  布拉布斯警长
What?! You take that back, Sheriff Blubs!
你在开玩笑吧  肯定会有线索和动机啊
You're kidding, right? There must be evidence, motives.
-如果你需要的话我也可以帮忙啊  -他很擅长的
- Ya know, I could help, if you want. - He's really good.
他查出了那个偷吃我们罐头的贼
He figured out who was eating our tin cans.
所有的证据都指向了山羊
All signs pointed to the goat.
对啊对啊  让这孩子帮忙吧
Yeah, yeah, let the boy help.
他脑子挺聪明的
He's got a little brain up in his head.
唔  瞧瞧现在是什么情况
Whoo! Would you look at what we got here!
这个城里来的毛头小子想用他的
City boy thinks he's gonna solve a mystery
高科技手机解决这个疑案
with his fancy computer phone!
城里小毛孩  城里小毛孩
City Bo-oy! City Bo-oy!
你真天真
You are adorable.
天真
Adorable?
听着  小孩儿
Look P.J.'s,
你还是把这个案子留给成年人来破吧
how about you leave the investigatin' to the grown-ups?
所有单位注意
<i>Attention, all units.</i>
史蒂夫要把一整个哈密瓜塞进他嘴里
<i>Steve is going to fit an entire cantaloupe in his mouth.</i>
重复一遍  一整个哈密瓜
<i>Repeat, an entire cantaloupe.</i>
-是报警主机  -我们走
- It's a 2316! - Let's move.
我受够了  梅宝  咱俩把这个混蛋揪出来
That's it! Mabel, you and me are going to find the jerk who did this
找到蜡像的头
and get back that head!
我倒要看看是谁天真
Then we'll see who's <i>adorable.</i>
噢  你打喷嚏跟小猫咪似的
Aw. You sneeze like a kitten.
蜡像斯坦丢了脑袋
Wax Stan has lost his head,
而我们将会找到它
and it's up to us to find it.
揭幕会上有很多不满的顾客
There were a lot of unhappy customers at the unveiling.
任何人都有可能是谋杀嫌疑犯
The murderer could have been anyone.
对呀  我们也是嫌疑犯
Yeah! Even us!
在这个小镇  没什么是不可能的  鬼怪  僵尸
In this town, anything is possible, ghosts, zombies...
我们找到线索可能要花上几个月的时间呢
could be months before we find our first clue.
嘿  看呐  有个线索
Hey, look, a clue!
粗毛地毯上的脚印
Footprints in the shag carpet.
好奇怪啊  那里面有个洞
That's weird. They've got a hole in them.
它们通向
And they're leading to...
你怎么看
So what do you think?
我觉得  这是个斧子
In my opinion, this is an ax.
等一下  那个伐木工人
Wait a minute... the lumberjack!
就是他
Of course!
吃我一拳
In your face!
他没得到免费匹萨的时候都气爆了
He was furious when he didn't get that free pizza.
愤怒到足以构成谋杀动机
Furious enough for murder!
哦  你们是说大胡子丹
Oh, you mean Manley Dan?
他经常出没于市中心的疯狂赛车手俱乐部
He hangs out at this crazy-intense biker joint downtown.
那儿就是我们的目的地了
Then <i>that's </i>where we're going.
哥们儿  帅呆了
Dude, this is awesome.
你们两个看起来就像是神探二人组
You two are like the mystery twins.
少来
Don't call us that.
嘿  帮帮忙抬这个棺材好吗
Hey, gimme a hand with this coffin, will ya?
我要给蜡像斯坦举行一个追悼会
I'm doing a memorial service for wax Stan.
小型而豪华追悼会
Something small, but classy.
- 哦  - 不好意思  斯坦叔公
- Ooh! - Sorry, Grunkle Stan,
-这件案子有很大的突破 -大突破
- But we've got a big break in the case. - Break in the case!
我们现在要去趟城里审讯犯人
We're heading into town right now to interrogate the murderer.
我们有这个证据  斧子
We have an ax! Ree! Ree! Ree!
这不像是负责任的父母会允许你们做的事
Seems like the kind of thing a responsible parent wouldn't want you doing.
好在我是你们的叔公  帮我报仇吧  孩子们
Good thing I'm an uncle. Avenge me, kids!
为我复仇吧
Avenge me!!!
就是这儿了
This is the place.
假身份证呢
Got the fake I.D.'s?
这上面什么都没有
Here goes nothing.
不好意思我们不为矮人提供服务
Sorry, but we don't serve minors.
你大爷的
Dagnabbit!
我们是来这儿审问伐木工人大胡子丹的
We're here to interrogate Manley Dan the lumberjack
他杀害了蜡像斯坦
for the murder of wax Stan.
请进
Works for me.
他在休息
He's resting.
好啦  我们尽量融入这个场合  好吧
All right, let's just try to blend in, okay?
你就放心吧  亲
You got it, dipping sauce.
嘿  你好  餐馆男
Hey, there, fellow restaurant patron!
大胡子丹  正是我要找的人
Manley Dan! Just the guy I wanted to see.
-你昨晚在哪儿  -揍钟
- Where were you last night? - Punchin' the clock.
你在工作
You were at work?
没有  我昨晚在揍那个钟
No, I was <i>punchin' </i>that clock!
十点  正是案发的时间
Ten o'clock. The time of the murder.
那我猜你应该从来没见过这个吗
So I guess you've never seen <i>this </i>before?
-给我听着  小姑娘  -嘿  其实我是
- Listen, little girl... - Hey, actually, I'm...
那个斧子给我剔牙都不够
I wouldn't pick my teeth with that ax!
那是个左手斧  我惯用右手
It's left-handed. I only use my right hand.
最爷们儿的手
The manly hand!
好样的  好样的
Hit him! Hit him!
左手斧吗
Left-handed...
三  四  五  六
Three, four, five, six.
哦  你会娶到美女做老婆
Oh! Your wife is gonna be beautiful.
好耶
Yes!
梅宝  案件有了大突破
Mabel, big break in the case!
但是我老婆会爱我吗
But will she love me?
这是一个左手斧
It's a left-handed ax.
这些是嫌疑人
These are all our suspects.
大胡子丹不是左撇子
Manley Dan is right-handed.
也就是说只要我们找出左撇子的嫌犯来
That means all we gotta do is find our left-handed suspect
-案子就破了  -哦  太棒了
- and we've got our killer. - Oh, man!
我们今天人品大爆发啦
We are on <i>fire </i>today!
我们一定要揪出凶手
Let's find that murderer.
梅宝  单子上就剩一个嫌疑人了
Mabel! There's only one person left on this list!
对了  完全说得通
Of course! It all adds up.
你们俩毛头最好有万全把握
You kids better be right about this,
不然可就永远都没法知道谜底了
or you'll never hear the end of it.
证据确凿  无可辩驳
The evidence is irrefutable.
无可辩驳
It's <i>so </i>irrefutable.
我有机会用警棍喽
I'm gonna get to use my night stick!
准备好了吗  小兄弟
You ready, little fella?
数三下  一  二
On three. One, two...
-嘿哈  -不许动  突袭搜查
- Heeyaw! - Nobody move! This is a raid!
这是什么  突袭搜查
What is this, some kind of raid?
决心男托比
Toby determined,
你因涉嫌谋杀蜡像斯坦被捕了
you're under arrest for the murder of the wax body of Grunkle Stan!
你有权仰慕我们
You have the right to remain impressed
出色的侦查工作
with our awesome detective work.
我的那个天哪
Gobbling goose feathers!
我不明白
I don't understand!
那就让我解释给你听吧
Then allow me to explain.
你原本希望斯坦叔公的发布会
<i>You were hoping that Grunkle Stan's new attraction</i>
能拯救你每况愈下的报纸发行量
<i>would be the story that saved your failing newspaper.</i>
却不曾想这个发布会搞砸了
<i>But when the show was a flop,</i>
所以你就自己导演了一个头条新闻
<i>you decided to go out and make your own headline.</i>
百密终有一疏
But you were sloppy,
所有的线索
<i>and all the clues pointed to</i>
都把罪犯锁定成一个穿着破鞋的左撇子
<i>a shabby-shoed reporter who was caught left-handed!</i>
决心男托比  你栽了
Toby determined, you're yesterday's news.
小子  处理这种事情
Boy, your little knees must be sore
你下结论还太早了点吧
from jumping to conclusions!
我对这事儿可是一丁点都不知情
I had nothing to do with that murder.
-我就说嘛  等等  -哈  你能重复一下
- I knew it! Wait... what...? - Huh? Could you repeat...
那么入室谋杀那天晚上你到底在哪儿呢
Then where were you the night of the break-in?
我们终于可以独处啦
<i>Finally we can be alone,</i>
女记者珊多拉・西梅内斯的纸板
<i>cardboard cut-out of female news reporter Shandra Jimenez!</i>
没有犯罪时间  托比  你没有嫌疑了
Time stamp confirms it. Toby, you're off the hook,
-你这个怪胎  -好耶
- you freak of nature. - Hurray!
但是  肯定是他没错啊  快检查斧子上面的指纹
But... but it <i>has </i>to be him! Check the ax for fingerprints.
根本没有指纹
No prints at all.
没有指纹
No prints?
嘿  我给你弄个头条吧
Hey, I got a headline for ya:
“城里毛头小屁孩浪费大家的时间”
"City kids waste everyone's time."
孩子  我要是你们我会感觉相当丢人呢
Boy, I'd be pretty embarrassed if I was you two!
孩子们  苏斯
Kids, Soos,
蜡像们
lifeless wax figures,
感谢你们的到来
thank you all for coming.
有人可能会说  爱上自己的蜡像
Some people might say that it's wrong for a man
是不对的
to love a wax replica of himself.
-他们是错的  -别激动  苏斯
- They're wrong! - Easy, Soos.
蜡像斯坦  我希望你在天堂有包可以扒
Wax Stan, I hope you're pickin' pockets in wax heaven.
对不起  我的眼睛进东西了
I'm sorry, I got glitter in my eye!
哦  伙计
Oh, dude!
哎  也许那些警察对我的看法是对的
Huh. Those cops were right about me.
迪普  我们已经有了这么多进展了  不能现在放弃啊
Dipper, we've come so far. We can't give up now.
可是我已经把能想到的都想到了
But I considered everything...
凶器  动机  线索
the weapon, the motive, the clues...
哎  蜡像斯坦的鞋底有个洞
Huh. Wax Stan's shoe has a hole in it.
每个蜡像的脚底都有洞啊
All the wax guys have that.
这样他们才能固定在他们的位置上啊
It's where the pole thingie attaches to their stand dealies.
等一下
Wait a minute!
什么东西脚下有洞却没有指纹
What has holes in its shoes and no fingerprints?
梅宝  凶手就
Mabel! The murderers are...
站在你们身后
standing right behind you?
蜡像夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Wax Sherlock Holmes!
蜡像莎士比亚
Wax Shakespeare!
-蜡像库里奥  -咋了  福尔摩斯
- Wax Coolio? - What's up, Homes?
哦  天呐  地啊
Oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh.
恭喜啊  两个业余侦探
Congratulations, my two amateur sleuths.
你们已经破了这个案子了
You've unburied the truth!
现在我们要解决了你们
And now we're going to bury <i>you.</i>
了不起啊  迪普・派恩斯
Bravo, Dipper Pines!
你竟然发现了我们的小秘密
You've discovered our little secret.
给点掌声吧伙计们
Applaud, everyone!
讽刺的掌声响起来
Applaud sarcastically!
啊  不行  这个听起来太真诚了
Uh, no, that sounds too sincere.
慢点拍  就是这样
Slow clap. <i>There </i>we go.
高傲一点
Nice and condescending.
但是这怎么可能呢  你们是蜡做的啊
But how is this possible? You're made of wax!
你们难道会  魔法
Are you... Magic?
我们会魔法  她想知道我们会不会魔法
Are we magic? She wants to know if we're magic!
-我们是被诅咒的  -被诅咒  被诅咒
- We're cursed! - Cursed! Cursed!
我们被诅咒在满月的时候活过来
Cursed to come to life whenever the moon is waxing.
我们是很多年以前被你叔公在旧货甩卖上买回来的
Your uncle bought us many years ago at a garage sale.
是个闹鬼的旧货甩卖会啊  小子
A <i>haunted </i>garage sale, son!
我必须警告你  这些塑像你买走可是要付出代价的
I must warn, the statues come at a terrible price.
二十美元  我只要趁你没看见的时候拿走就好了啊
Twenty dollars?! I'll just take 'em when you're not looking.
-什么  -我说我要抢劫你
- What? - I said I was gonna rob ya.
随后  带着神秘色彩的蜡像展览诞生了
<i>And so the mystery shack wax collection was born.</i>
我们白天沦为人们的玩物
<i>By day we would be the playthings of man.</i>
但是当你叔公睡着的时候  我们就是夜晚的统治者了
<i>But when your uncle was asleep, we would rule the night.</i>
- 嘿  跟你说了别揪了  -你打我呀
- Hey. I told you to stop that. - Make me.
那段时间对我们这些受诅咒的蜡像来说是多么美好啊
<i>It was a charmed life for us cursed beings.</i>
直到 你叔公关闭了展览
<i>That is, until your uncle closed up shop.</i>
我们为报复斯坦等了整整十年
<i>We've been waiting ten years to get our revenge on Stan</i>
谁让他把我们锁起来的
<i>for locking us away.</i>
但是我们报复错了人
<i>But we got the wrong guy.</i>
所以你们其实是想杀了真正的斯坦叔公
So you were trying to murder Grunkle Stan for <i>real?</i>
你一直都是对的  迪普  蜡像真的挺慎人的
You were right all along, Dipper! Wax people <i>are </i>creepy!
够了  既然你们知道了我们的秘密
Enough! Now that you know our secret,
你们就必须死
you must die.
我们该怎么办  我们该怎么办
What do we do? What do we do?!
我也不知道
I don't know!
对呀  我们可以用任何热的东西把他们融化
That's it! We can melt them with hotty melty things!
都给我后退  小心我把你们化成蜡烛
Anyone move, and we'll melt you into candles!
装饰性的蜡烛
<i>Decorative </i>candles!
你们真的以为可以打败我们吗
You really think you can defeat <i>us?</i>
-总要试一试嘛  对吧  -我也不确定哎
- It's worth a shot, I guess. - I'm not really sure.
这就对了  进攻
So be it. Attack!
采访这个吧  拉里・金
Interview <i>this, </i>Larry King!
我的脖子  我漂亮的脖子
My neck! My beautiful neck!
那这个当笑话吧  格劳乔
Joke's on you, Groucho!
我听说过一个尖刻的评论  但是这个太荒谬了
I've heard about a cutting remark, but this is ridiculous.
嘿  我手里的东西呢
Hey, why is there nothing in my hand?
哈  成吉思汗  你的衰落简直比
Ha! Genghis Khan, you fell harder than the...
呃  金朝还快
Ah, I don't know, Jin Dynasty?
随便啦
Yeah. All right.
-怎么了  -迪普小心
- What's up with that? - Dipper, watch out!
好吧  让我们来个了结吧
All right, let's get this taken care of.
接着
Catch!
没有了你们家的阻碍
Once your family is out of the way,
我们就又是这里夜晚的主宰者了
we'll rule the night once again!
没戏
Don't count on it!
给我回来  小兔崽子
Come back here, you brat!
你真的以为你可以战胜我吗  小子
You really think you can outwit me, boy?
我可是残暴的夏洛克・福尔摩斯
I'm Sherlock bleeding Holmes!
你见过我的放大镜吗
Have you <i>seen </i>my magnifying glass?!
超级大哦
It's enormous!
有遗言吗
Any last words?
呃  你擦防晒霜了吗
Um... You got any sun screen?
有没有  什么
Got any... What?!
-不 - 你知道  让我把你引到外面来
- No. - You know, letting me lead you outside,
或许不是你最明智的选择哟
Probably not your sharpest decision.
我居然输给了一个穿短裤的小毛孩子
Outsmarted by a child in short pants!
不
Noooo!
胡说  骗子
Fiddlesticks! Humbugs!
简直是胡闹
It's a total kerfuffle!
简直是胡闹啊
What a hullaballoo!
结案
Case closed.
哈哈哈  你打喷嚏跟小猫眯似的
Ha ha ha! You sneeze like a kitten.
警察们是对的  你真天真
Those policemen were right, you're adorable.
天真
Adorable!!!
尽管被这俩虐成这个德性
Though our group been cleft in twain
蜡像军团一定东山再起
Man of wax shall rise again!
-你会背五行打油诗吗 -呃
- You know any limericks? - Uh...
从前有个从肯塔基来的家伙
There once was a dude from Kentucky...
-不对  -啊
- Nope. - Aaah!
迪普  你没事儿
Dipper! You're okay!
你解决了这个案子呢
You solved the mystery after all.
没有我的好帮手  我自己一个人也完成不了呀
I couldn't have done it without my sidekick.
无心冒犯  迪普  恐怕你才是那个帮手吧
No offense, Dipper, but you're the sidekick.
什么  谁说的  大家是这样说的吗  你听见了
What? Says who? Are people saying that? Have you heard that?
我的个神啊
Hot Belgian waffles!
我的陈列室里发生了什么
What happened to my parlor?!
你的蜡像们太邪恶了
Your wax figures turned out to be evil,
所以我们把它们打入地狱啦
so we fought them to the death!
我砍了拉里・金的头
I decapitated Larry King.
哈哈  你们太有想象力了
Ha ha! You kids and your imaginations.
也有好的一面哟  瞧瞧我们找到了什么
On the bright side, though, look what we found.
我的脑袋  哈哈
My head! Ha ha!
我想死它了
I missed this guy.
做的不错  孩子们
You done good, kids!
站好  钻钻头来庆祝一下吧
Line up for some affectionate noogying.
我不确定自己想不想哎  没有别的选择了吗
I'm not so sure about that. Is there any other alternative?
哈哈  钻钻钻
Ha ha! Noogy, noogy, noogy!
侦探小子  案子破了吗
Solve the case yet, boy?
我怎么有预感你要说“没有”呢
I'm so confident you're gonna say no
就让我慢慢小啜一口咖啡听你哭诉吧
that I'm gonna take a long, slow sip from my cup of coffee.
其实  答案是  破了
Actually, the answer is yes.
-烫死了  烫死了 -我的眼睛
- It burns! It burns! - My eyes!
他们肯定烫伤了
They got scalded!
你确定你把蜡像们都搞定了吗
So, did you get rid of <i>all </i>the wax figures?
我有百分之九十九的把握
I am 99% sure that I did.
对我来说足够啦
Good enough for me.
你是个肥老鼠  对吧
So, you're a rat. Tell me about that.
嘿  回来
Hey! Get back here!
我在跳
I'm hopping!
我跟在一只偷了我耳朵的老鼠后面跳
I'm hopping after a rat that stole my ear!
嗯  嘿  迪普
Hmm. Hey, Dipper,
你觉得哪件比较好呢
what do you think is better,
亮片衫还是羊驼毛衫呢
sequins or llama hair?
羊驼毛衫
The llama hair.
羊驼是大自然最伟大的勇士
Llamas are nature's greatest warriors.
谢啦  迪普
Thanks, Dipper!